<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>linux on Fireship</title>
    <link>https://fireship.io/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in linux on Fireship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 13:08:58 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fireship.io/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Carta de achamento da America Portuguesa</title>
      <link>https://fireship.io/lessons/ffmpeg-useful-techniques/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 13:08:58 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fireship.io/lessons/ffmpeg-useful-techniques/</guid>
      <description>Sobre a carta de Achamento do Brasil Questões 1. Como são descritos os Ameríndios? Pardos Bons rostos, bons narizes; Bem feitos. Sem-vergonhas(literalmente) 2. Que presentes lhe são dados Galinha(s) Ramal Sombreiro 3. Como se chamava o piloto? Afonso Lopes 4. Qual a importância dos pilotos neste texto? Eram o primeiro à tomar iniciativa nas expedições. 5. ø 6.Que costumes distintos surpreendem os portugues? Nudez &amp;amp; inocência. 7. Como é descrito o capitão Bem vestido, usava joias « &amp;ldquo;(&amp;hellip;), com um colar de ouro mui grande ao pescoço(&amp;hellip;) &amp;quot; » 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Informatics</title>
      <link>https://fireship.io/lessons/node-crypto-examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 13:08:58 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fireship.io/lessons/node-crypto-examples/</guid>
      <description>[Informatics] First draft :bulb:I cannot garantee that this project will turn out as i expect. This will be my first time in this type of activity. :sunglasses: Red-Piling classes Raise awareness over how people are being exploited ( without their knowlodge). This classes will be for general software and privacy knowlodge.
:feet: Roadmap Ask class-mates what are they think about the project. Ask permission to be granted ( Ask the CAS&amp;rsquo;s counceilour) 1 Linux installation ) PopOS or Artix (with larbs) 2 Vim&amp;rsquo;s lecture ) touch ) make directories ) Basic VIM commands ) Write and save Documents 3 Microsoft is a Craphole 4 Why Whatsapp is crap and Signal is way supperior 5 Goals I don&#39;t even know.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rustling</title>
      <link>https://fireship.io/lessons/advanced-firestore-nosql-data-structure-examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 13:08:58 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fireship.io/lessons/advanced-firestore-nosql-data-structure-examples/</guid>
      <description>Rustling&amp;rsquo;s progress (status)
First day Heute, habe ich 5.3 perzent gemacht. Eu nao olhei nenhuma resposta. Apenas vi um pouco [deste vídeo](https://piped.video/watch?v=G3Vr-yswlaU) para poder situar-me. My solutions be like: 🤨📂 click in the folder</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cron Example Schedules</title>
      <link>https://fireship.io/snippets/crontab-crash-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 07:41:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fireship.io/snippets/crontab-crash-course/</guid>
      <description>Cron is a long-running process used on Linux servers that ticks at specific times based on the crontab pattern (with a minimum of 1 minute of granularity). It is used to setup cronjobs, which are background tasks that get executed at a specific time or interval. Also, Firebase now has a time-triggered Cloud Function that can be set with crontab. The following guide will teach you how to schedule cronjobs in this format.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
