<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Android on Fireship</title>
    <link>https://fireship.io/tags/android/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Android on Fireship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 12:14:09 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fireship.io/tags/android/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Flutter File Uploads</title>
      <link>https://fireship.io/lessons/flutter-file-uploads-cloud-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 12:14:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fireship.io/lessons/flutter-file-uploads-cloud-storage/</guid>
      <description>Camera apps are one of the most popular niches in the market, with the recent viral growth of FaceApp being a prime example. There are a variety of plugins for Flutter that make camera-based features easy to develop, and when combined with Firebase the results can be easily uploaded your backend cloud infrastructure. The following lesson demonstrates the following features:
Capture images from the device camera or image gallery. Crop, rotate, and resize an image file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In App Purchases in Flutter</title>
      <link>https://fireship.io/lessons/flutter-inapp-purchases/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 06:14:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fireship.io/lessons/flutter-inapp-purchases/</guid>
      <description>Flutter recently launched official support for In App Purchases (IAP) and provides a unified plugin for both iOS and Android. Native mobile apps that collect payments for digital goods on the Apple App Store and/or Google Play Store are typically required to use the In App Purchases API, which means services like Stripe and Paypal are out of the question (with the exception of payments for physically shipped goods). In reality, In App Purchases are far more lucrative for digital products, with the game Candy Crush generating $4MM in revenue per day in 2018.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trusted Web Activity - PWA to Play Store Guide</title>
      <link>https://fireship.io/lessons/pwa-to-play-store/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 10:27:58 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fireship.io/lessons/pwa-to-play-store/</guid>
      <description>Web developers already have a variety of interesting options for using JavaScript to write native mobile apps with tools like React Native, Cordova/Ionic, NativeScript, just to name a few. I&amp;rsquo;ve spent many hours brainstorming with clients on this topic and recently summed up my thoughts about Hybrid App development, but there&amp;rsquo;s a brand new strategy to add to the list&amp;hellip; Trusted Web Activities (TWA). The following guide will show you how to covert any progressive web app to an Android App on the Google Play Store.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
