<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Contributors on Fireship</title>
    <link>https://fireship.io/contributors/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Contributors on Fireship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fireship.io/contributors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sabz</title>
      <link>https://fireship.io/contributors/sabz/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fireship.io/contributors/sabz/</guid>
      <description>Sabz is a self-taught developer &amp;amp;&amp;amp; designer. He is interested in web, desktop development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alex Guja</title>
      <link>https://fireship.io/contributors/alex-guja/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 09:32:30 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fireship.io/contributors/alex-guja/</guid>
      <description>Alex is a full-stack developer based in Europe. He is interested in web development, mobile apps, data engineering, and cloud technologies. In his free time, he enjoys reading, writes music, and likes to meet new people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kyle Leary</title>
      <link>https://fireship.io/contributors/kyle-leary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 22:00:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fireship.io/contributors/kyle-leary/</guid>
      <description>Kyle aka &amp;ldquo;Klutch&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;KlutchDev&amp;rdquo; is a battle-hardened fullstack JavaScript/React &amp;amp;&amp;amp; Firebase developer from western Massachusetts. Klutch is currently learning Rust, TypeScript, and preparing for the OSWE exam. When not writing code he is relaxing at home with his long time sweetheart Chelsea and cats Murph/Zelda or shredding guitar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jeff Delaney</title>
      <link>https://fireship.io/contributors/jeff-delaney/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 09:32:30 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fireship.io/contributors/jeff-delaney/</guid>
      <description>Jeff Delaney is a Google Developer Expert and the creator of fireship.io. When not writing code, he is out seeking adventure with his wife and 3 boys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>David Bautista</title>
      <link>https://fireship.io/contributors/david-bautista/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 13:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fireship.io/contributors/david-bautista/</guid>
      <description>David Bautista is a Software Engineer from Mexico.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Johan Walhout</title>
      <link>https://fireship.io/contributors/johan-walhout/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fireship.io/contributors/johan-walhout/</guid>
      <description>Johan is a software engineer developing apps and webapplications in Angular 2+, VueJS, Nodejs and Dart/Flutter. When he is not working on new projects, he enjoy to have adventures with his wife, four boys and a dog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lenny Cunningham</title>
      <link>https://fireship.io/contributors/lenny-cunningham/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fireship.io/contributors/lenny-cunningham/</guid>
      <description>Lenny is a self taught hobbiest for WebApp Development. Owns Acadiana Apps. A small company specializing in custom web app development, and Google Apps Script integrations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Darshan Gowda</title>
      <link>https://fireship.io/contributors/darshan-gowda/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fireship.io/contributors/darshan-gowda/</guid>
      <description>Darshan is a freelancer from Bangalore, India. He loves to code, teach and play basketball.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arjun Yelamanchili</title>
      <link>https://fireship.io/contributors/arjun-yelamanchili/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 10:22:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fireship.io/contributors/arjun-yelamanchili/</guid>
      <description>Arjun is a full-stack developer and future blockchain billionaire based in Denver, CO</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dominik Šimoník</title>
      <link>https://fireship.io/contributors/dominik-simonik/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 10:22:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fireship.io/contributors/dominik-simonik/</guid>
      <description>Dominik Šimoník is software engineer developing apps in Angular, Java, Dart, Nodejs and Ruby. He is GDG Organizer and lector for women at community Czechitas in the Czech republic. When he is not at the computer he does some sort of geek things like drone races etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patrick Mullot</title>
      <link>https://fireship.io/contributors/patrick-mullot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 10:22:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fireship.io/contributors/patrick-mullot/</guid>
      <description>Patrick is a part-time full-stack developer, with (too) many years of experience as a Project Developer and programmer. He now specializes in the Firebase ecosystem. When not in his tech-cave, he enjoys traveling and have long walks with his family and their 4 legged friends</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radi Cho</title>
      <link>https://fireship.io/contributors/radi-cho/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 10:22:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fireship.io/contributors/radi-cho/</guid>
      <description>Radi is a student, developing futuristic projects, websites and Android apps as a hobby. He also plays with ML, IoT, Cloud services and anything else that looks like the next big thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zack DeRose</title>
      <link>https://fireship.io/contributors/zack-derose/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 10:22:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fireship.io/contributors/zack-derose/</guid>
      <description>Zack is a GDE for Google, as well as an Engineer and Engineering Manager for Nx, and an avid fan of Supabase.
Zack always bets on Javascript (and Typescript), but he also enjoys Postgres, making videos, and has been dabbling recently in shit-posting on Twitter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finn Krestel</title>
      <link>https://fireship.io/contributors/finn-krestel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fireship.io/contributors/finn-krestel/</guid>
      <description>Finn Krestel is a Java, JavaScript, CSS and HTML developer. He mainly uses React or Preact for interactive web applications. Next.js is his favorite SSR framework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jarrett Helton</title>
      <link>https://fireship.io/contributors/jarrett-helton/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fireship.io/contributors/jarrett-helton/</guid>
      <description>Jarrett is a code enthusiast from the Central Michigan area. He is a jack-of-all-trades engineer with experiences in just about everything you can shake a stick at. When not slangin&amp;rsquo; code for federal health care contracts, he finds enjoyment with side projects through different LLCs and is always open for more consultations. On the occasion he is not coding or sleeping, you can find him chilling with his wife and daughter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jeroen Ouwehand</title>
      <link>https://fireship.io/contributors/jeroen.ouwehand/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fireship.io/contributors/jeroen.ouwehand/</guid>
      <description>Jeroen is a full-stack developer from Rotterdam (The Netherlands) and is currently working for a bank. Sometimes writes posts on Medium or contribute on Github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jorge Dacosta</title>
      <link>https://fireship.io/contributors/jorge-dacosta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fireship.io/contributors/jorge-dacosta/</guid>
      <description>Jorge Dacosta is Co-Founder of Splash Ink (🇦🇴 🇿🇦), Graphic Designer and Open Source (OSS) enthusiast who loves share his knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marc Stammerjohann</title>
      <link>https://fireship.io/contributors/marc-stammerjohann/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fireship.io/contributors/marc-stammerjohann/</guid>
      <description>Marc Stammerjohann is a freelance full-stack software engineer developing apps with Ionic, Angular, Typescript, Java and Kotlin. He is interested in Web Components, nest and Prisma lately. In his free time he enjoys inline skating, traveling, diving and reading books.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shawn Eubanks</title>
      <link>https://fireship.io/contributors/shawn-eubanks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fireship.io/contributors/shawn-eubanks/</guid>
      <description>devEUBE = technology geek and expert problem solver. I love to learn anything new, and I am especially interested and passionate about emerging technologies in cloud computing and web development. I am driven and passionate about sharing skills and knowledge with others and helping others succeed using new and innovative technologies.
Passionate Hobbies: Learning New Media, Gaming and Design / Development of media and web presences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wei Lun</title>
      <link>https://fireship.io/contributors/weilun/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fireship.io/contributors/weilun/</guid>
      <description>Wei Lun is a bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree student in Software Engineering based in Malaysia. He actively learning trendy technologies, mainly in web, mobile, cloud technologies and solution architect.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
