<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>gcp on Fireship</title>
    <link>https://fireship.io/tags/gcp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in gcp on Fireship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 13:08:29 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fireship.io/tags/gcp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Google Secret Manager with Firebase</title>
      <link>https://fireship.io/lessons/secret-manager-with-firebase/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 13:08:29 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fireship.io/lessons/secret-manager-with-firebase/</guid>
      <description>Secret Manager is a new service on Google Cloud that allows us to store and version sensitive data like private API keys and passwords, then access it from any cloud service. It provides encryption, audit logging, versioning, and IAM roles for secure fine-grained control over sensitive information.
A common use-case for a Firebase apps is the management of secret API keys in a Cloud Function. The following lesson will teach you how add secrets via the Google Cloud console, then read them from a Firebase Cloud Function with Node.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Cloud Computing in 2020?</title>
      <link>https://fireship.io/lessons/cloud-computing-in-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 11:59:07 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fireship.io/lessons/cloud-computing-in-2020/</guid>
      <description>Data Sources Gartner Forecasts Forbes Enterprise Computing Flexera Report 2019 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firebase Microservices With Cloud Run</title>
      <link>https://fireship.io/lessons/firebase-microservices-with-cloud-run/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 10:25:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fireship.io/lessons/firebase-microservices-with-cloud-run/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday Google Cloud released a game-changing new product called Cloud Run that allows you to run and scale stateless Docker containers in a serverless execution environment powered by Knative.
Benefits
Run backend microservices with any programming language and/or dependencies. Serverless pricing, only pay for what you use. Scale automatically. Prevent cloud vendor lock-in. Some of the things you might do with it&amp;hellip;
Deploy server-rendered SSR frontend apps to Firebase Hosting, like Angular Universal, Nuxt, or Next.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Coder to Run VS Code on Google Cloud</title>
      <link>https://fireship.io/lessons/vscode-cloud-coder-tensorflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 05:49:52 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fireship.io/lessons/vscode-cloud-coder-tensorflow/</guid>
      <description>Turning VS Code into a full IDE requires you to carefully blend your favorite extensions and packages for the type of development work you perform. It can take hours or even days to get your development environment fine-tuned for optimal productivity. But what happens upgrade to a new computer? Or need to share your IDE with somebody on the other side of the world? Or maybe you just need more compute resources&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Cloud Vision with Ionic - Not Hotdog App</title>
      <link>https://fireship.io/lessons/google-cloud-vision-with-ionic-and-firebase/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 15:00:49 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fireship.io/lessons/google-cloud-vision-with-ionic-and-firebase/</guid>
      <description>In this lesson, we&amp;rsquo;re going to combine Google&amp;rsquo;s Google&amp;rsquo;s Cloud Vision API with Ionic and Firebase to create a native mobile app that can automatically label and tag images. But most importantly, it can determine if an image is a hotdog or not - just like the SeeFood app that made Jin Yang very rich.
Just a few years ago, this technology would have been unreachable by the average developer. You would need to train your own deep neural network on tens-of-thousands of images with massive amounts of computing power.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
