<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sql on Fireship</title>
    <link>https://fireship.io/tags/sql/</link>
    <description>Recent content in sql on Fireship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 16:09:39 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fireship.io/tags/sql/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Seven Database Paradigms</title>
      <link>https://fireship.io/lessons/top-seven-database-paradigms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 16:09:39 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fireship.io/lessons/top-seven-database-paradigms/</guid>
      <description>Choose the right database for the job 🔨
Database Paradigms Explained Visually Key-Value Popular Key-Value Databases: Redis, Memcached, Etcd
key value database diagram
Wide Column Popular Wide-Column Databases: Cassandra, Apache HBase
wide column database diagram
Document Oriented Popular Document Databases: MongoDB, Firestore, CouchDB
document database diagram
Relational Popular Relational Databases: MySQL, Postgres, SQL Server, CockroachDB
Graph Popular Graph Databases: Neo4j, DGraph, Janus Graph
Search Engine Popular Search Databases: ElasticSearch, Algolia, MeiliSearch</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MySQL on Cloud Functions</title>
      <link>https://fireship.io/lessons/sql-firebase-typeorm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 12:31:06 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fireship.io/lessons/sql-firebase-typeorm/</guid>
      <description>Firebase&amp;rsquo;s NoSQL databases are excellent for flexibility and scale, but there are times when a traditional relational SQL database is a better tool for the job (or you may not have a choice with a legacy system). Does that mean you should ditch the Firebase platform altogether? Of course not! In fact, connecting a Cloud SQL instance to Firebase Cloud Functions is one of the easiest ways to hook up a database to a web or mobile app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BigQuery ML Quickstart</title>
      <link>https://fireship.io/lessons/bigquery-ml-quickstart/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 18:23:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fireship.io/lessons/bigquery-ml-quickstart/</guid>
      <description>BigQuery is a serverless Data Warehouse that makes it easy to process and query massive amounts of data. It supports standard SQL queries in a web-based UI, via the command line, or with a variety of client libraries. In addition, it recently landed support for integrated machine learning, allowing you to build predictive models without data science skills.
What can you do with Big Query?
Stream data to business intelligence tools like Data Studio, Tableau, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firestore NoSQL Relational Data Modeling</title>
      <link>https://fireship.io/lessons/firestore-nosql-data-modeling-by-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 15:20:23 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fireship.io/lessons/firestore-nosql-data-modeling-by-example/</guid>
      <description>Looking for advanced data modeling concepts and examples? Take the Firestore Data Modeling Course.
Data modeling in a NoSQL environment is tricky - especially if you come from a RDBMS background (MySQL, Postgres, etc) because you will need to unlearn many of the core principles already solidified in your brain. Firestore uses a document-oriented NoSQL model, similar to MongoDB and CouchDB, which leads to fundamentally different data structuring decisions.
The goal of this lesson is to examine data modeling principles in Firestore with comparisons to SQL.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
