<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stripe on Fireship</title>
    <link>https://fireship.io/tags/stripe/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Stripe on Fireship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 10:23:30 -0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fireship.io/tags/stripe/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Stripe Payments JavaScript Course</title>
      <link>https://fireship.io/courses/stripe-js/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 10:23:30 -0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fireship.io/courses/stripe-js/</guid>
      <description>This course has been deprecated. A completely new Stripe course will replace this content in the near future (Spring 2023). The Stripe Payments JavaScript Course is a project-based guide to building fullstack payment solutions on the web with Node.js and React.
The goal is to provide a solid foundation for app monetization 💸 by implementing common use-cases with Stripe APIs including Checkout, Payment Intents, and Billing.
Updated May 11th, 2020 Stripe API v2020-03-02</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>API Monetization with Stripe Metered Billing</title>
      <link>https://fireship.io/lessons/api-monetization-stripe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2021 10:12:58 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fireship.io/lessons/api-monetization-stripe/</guid>
      <description>Building a monetized API for a SaaS product might seem like a daunting task, but it&amp;rsquo;s actually relatively simple when you bring in tools like Stripe&amp;rsquo;s Metered Billing feature. There are 4 main steps in the process:
Create an API Subscribe a customer to a recurring subscription in Stripe Create custom API keys to authenticate requests to the API Report API usage to Stripe The following lesson demonstrates the backend flow for building API with Express.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stripe Payment Intents Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://fireship.io/lessons/stripe-payment-intents-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 18:05:34 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fireship.io/lessons/stripe-payment-intents-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>Stripe provides a huge API with everything you could ever want to build a complex payment system. Recent changes in the online payments landscape have resulted in significant changes to the API, most notably the Payment Intents API. The following lesson demonstrates two modern strategies for accepting one-time payments - (1) Checkout and (2) Stripe Elements with Payment Intents.
As of September 2019, many European banks now require their customers to validate payments using 3D secure standard or Strong Customer Authentication SCA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stripe Elements and Checkout with Angular</title>
      <link>https://fireship.io/lessons/stripe-elements-angular/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 08:48:04 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fireship.io/lessons/stripe-elements-angular/</guid>
      <description>💰 Are you building a payment solution with Stripe? Consider enrolling the Stripe JavaScript Master Course.
Stripe provides several JavaScript libraries - Stripe Elements &amp;amp; Checkout - that makes it easy to collect and validate payment sources like credit cards, bank accounts, and more. The following lesson will show you how to integrate Stripe&amp;rsquo;s clientside JS packages into an Angular application.
Step 0. Prerequisites This lesson only covers the frontend code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metered Stripe Subscription Billing</title>
      <link>https://fireship.io/lessons/saas-metered-subscriptions-with-stripe-billing-and-firebase/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2018 14:36:01 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fireship.io/lessons/saas-metered-subscriptions-with-stripe-billing-and-firebase/</guid>
      <description>💰 Are you building a payment solution with Stripe? Consider enrolling the Stripe JavaScript Master Course.
Today we will something very ambitious - our own Software-as-a-Service (SaaS) product that bills users based on metered usage. The app is a hypothetical project management tool with a pay-as-you-go billing system based on the volume of usage (just like the Blaze plan in Firebase). A user can create multiple projects, each at a cost of $1.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
